Finding Aid for the William Campbell Binkley Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Binkley, William Campbell Papers
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0042
17.64 linear feet
- Outgoing correspondence. Approximately 6,750 items, mostly carbon copies, dating from 1920 to 1970. Arranged chronologically. (Box 1-9)
  Box 1: 1920 -- 1935 (1-35)
  Box 2: 1936 -- Oct. 1938 (1-34)
  Box 3: Nov. 1938 -- 1941 (1-32)
  Box 4: 1942 -- June 1944 (1-31)
  Box 5: July 1944 -- Mar. 1946 (1-30)
  Box 6: Apr. 1946 -- June 1948 (1-29)
  Box 7: July 1948 -- May 1952 (1-32)
  Box 8: June 1952 -- May 1957 (1-30)
  Box 9: June 1957 -- Feb. 1970 (1-30)
- Incoming correspondence. Approximately 7,800 items, from about 1400 correspondents. Arranged alphabetically. (Box 10-24)
  Box 10: Abbott -- Bailey (1-13)
  Box 11: Baker -- Burnette (1-16)
  Box 12: Burt -- Cole (1-16)
  Box 13: Cole -- Davis (1-16)
  Box 14: Day -- Futrell (1-17)
  Box 15: Gage -- Haun (1-16)
  Box 16: Hay -- Jordan (1-15)
  Box 17: Josephson -- Malone (1-16)
  Box 18: Mamatey -- Moore (1-15)
  Box 19: Morgan -- Paine (1-15)
  Box 20: Paine -- Robison (1-16)
  Box 21: Roddis -- Stephenson (1-16)
  Box 22: Stephenson -- Thompson (1-12)
  Box 23: Thomson -- Williams (1-17)
  Box 24: Williams -- Zorn (1-6)
- Manuscript writings (Box 25)
- Articles, addresses, etc., arranged alphabetically: (Box 25-26)
  "The Activities of the Texas Revolutionary Army after San Jacinto"
  "Do the Americas Have a Common History? A United States View"
  "Frank Lawrence Owsley, 1890-1956"
  "Handicaps to Effective Research in Colleges"
  "A Historian looks at the National Union Catalog of Manuscript Collections"
  "A History of the Texan Revolution" (Knopf Fellowship application, 1940)
  "Independence and Political Stability"
  "New Mexico and the Santa Fe Expedition"
  "Our Latin American Neighbors"
  "Public Opinion and the Teaching of History"
  "Reports from a Texan Agent in New Mexico, 1849" ("Some Problems of the Historian")
  "Some Undeveloped Topics in Tennessee History"
  "Some Unwritten Pages in American History"
  "The South and the West"
  "The Texan Revolution"
  "The Texan Revolutionary Army after San Jacinto"
  "Two World Wars and American Historical Scholarship"
  "Walter Lynwood Fleming"
- Fleming Lectures: (Box 26)
  "Conditions in Texas on the Eve of the Revolution"
  "The Preliminaries of the Revolution"
  "The Struggle for the Federal Constitution"
- Book reviews, arranged alphabetically by author of book: (Box 26)
  Adams, America's Tragedy (1934)
  Bannon, Bolton and the Spanish Borderlands (1964)
  Barker, The Life of Stephen F. Austin (1925)
  ......, Mexico and Texas, 1821-1835 (1928) (w/ Castaneda, The Mexican Side of the Texan Revolution)
  ------, Readings in Texas History (1929)
  Beers, The Western Military Frontier, 1815-1846 (1935)
  Bloom, New Mexico History and Civics (1933)
  Clark, The Rampaging Frontier
  Falconer, Letters and Notes on the Texan Santa Fe Expedition, 1841-1842 (1930)
  Folmsbee, Sectionalism and Internal Improvements in Tennessee, 1796-1845 (1939)
  Forrest, Missions and Pueblos of the Old Southwest (1929)
  Gambrell, Anson Jones: The Last President of Texas (1948)
  Writing Southern History: Essays in Historiography in Honor of Fletcher M. Green (1965)
  Haley, George W. Littlefield, Texan (1943)
  Historical Records Survey, Inventory of the Colonial Archives of Texas, 1821-1837. No. 3, Municipality of Brazoria, 1832-1837 (1937)
  Konwiser, Texas Republic Postal System (1933)
  Mecham, Francisco de Ibarra and Nueva Vizcaya (1927)
  Molyneaux, The Romantic Story of Texas (1936)
  Parks, Felix Grundy: Champion of Democracy (1940)
  Reynolds, ed., As Our Neighbors See Us: Readings in the Relations of the United States and Latin America, 1820-1940 (1940)
  Rister, Robert E. Lee in Texas (1946)
  Robertson, History of the Latin-American Nations (1925)
  Schmitz, Texan Statecraft, 1836-1845 (1941)
  Smither, ed., Journals of the Fourth Congress of the Repub1ic of Texas, 1839-1840, to which are added the Relief Laws (1930-31)
  Stephenson, Southern History in the Making: Pioneer Historians of the South (1964)
  Streeter, Bibliography of Texas, 1795-1845. Part I, Texas Imprints (1955)
  Webb, The Texas Rangers: A Century of Frontier Defense (1935)
  White, ed., Messages of the Governors of Tennessee, Vol. VI, 1869-1883 (1963)
  Williams and Barker, eds., The Writings of Sam Houston, 1813-1863, Vol. I, 1813-1836 (1938); Vol. II, 1814-1842 (1939); Vol. Ill, 1822-1844 (1940); Vol. IV, 1821-1847 (1941); Vol. V, 1824-1854 (1941); Vol. VI, 1828-1858 (1941); Vol. VII, 1824-1860 (1942); Vol. VIII, 1825-1863 (1943).
  Winkler, ed., Check List of Texas Imprints, 1846-1860 (1949) 1 unidentified book review, title and author not given
- Southwestern Historical Quarterly summaries: summaries of articles by Biesele, Brown, Christensen, Donoghue, Henderson, Holden, Lesley, Myres, Rister, Smither, B. N. Taylor, P. S. Taylor, Winston (16 summaries) (Box 26 (12))
- Dictionary of American History and Dictionary of American Biography entries: articles on James Davis Porter, Edward Bushrod Stahlman, Alfred Alexander Taylor, Robert Love Taylor, Republic of Texas, John Wilson Thomas, and Peter Turney (Box 26 (13))
- Proposals and reports: Supplementary Statements to an Application for a Grant-in-Aid by the Social Science Research Council (n.d.); Report on the Work Done during the Simmer of 1933 on a Grant-in-Aid from the Social Science Research Council for Research on a History of the Republic of Texas; Statement Concerning the Research Project of William C. Binkley, submitted to the Committee on Grants-in-Aid of the Social Science Research Council in connection with a request for a grant-in-aid (n.d.); Supplementary Statement to an Application for a Summer Grant from the University Center Research Council (n.d.); Report to the University Center Research Council on Use of Summer Grant, 1949; Report to the Committee on Grants-in-Aid of the Social Science Research Council on the use which was made of a grant-in-aid for the year 1949-1950 (Box 26 (14))
- Miscellaneous writings: book review, The National Union Catalog of Manuscript Collections, 1962; article, "The Southwest: An Attempt at a Historical Definition"; obituaries, Andrew Bell Benedict, Louis Pelzer, Charles William Ramsdell (Box 26 (15))
- Published writings (offprints of articles and reviews): "A Historian Looks at the National Union Catalog of Manuscript Collections," "Two World Wars and American Historical Scholarship," reviews: Gambrell, Mirabeau Buonaparte Lamar, Troubadour and Crusader; Writing Southern History: Essays in Historiography in Honor of Fletcher M. Green; Stephenson, Southern History in the Making; White, ed., Messages of the Governors of Tennessee, Vol. VI, 1869-1883. (Box 26 (16))
- The Expansionist Movement in Texas, 1836-1850. Ph.D. thesis, University of California, 1923. Typed carbon. (Box 26 (17))
- Typescript of The Texas Revolution, chapters I-IV, with notes and comments, tentative outline, etc. (Box 27 (1-15))
- Chapter I, "The Establishment of Anglo-American Interests in Texas." 2 typed originals, with carbons and footnotes. (Box 27 (1-4))
- Chapter II, "Development of the Issue between Mexico and the Texans." 2 typed originals, with carbons and footnotes. (Box 27 (5-8))
- Chapter III, "Conditions in Texas on the Eve of the Revolution, 1833-1835." 2 typed originals, with carbons and footnotes. (Box 27 (9-11))
- Chapter IV, "The Preliminaries of the Revolution, 1834-1835." 1 typed original, with carbon and footnotes. (Box 27 (12-13))
- Chapter V, "The Struggle for the Federal Constitution." 1 typed original, with carbon and footnotes. (Box 27 (14-15))
- The Texas Revolution: notes and comments, outlines, etc. (Box 27 (16))
- Official Correspondence of the Texas Revolution: introductory material. (Box 27 (17-18))
- Official Correspondence of the Texas Revolution and other Texas correspondence: typed transcriptions and notes (Box 28-29)
- Texas correspondence, 1836 (Box 28 (1-3))
- Official Correspondence - miscellaneous research notes (Box 28 (4-5))
- Rusk correspondence, 1835-1836 (Box 28 (6-8))
- Miscellaneous Texas correspondence, 1839, 1850, etc. (Box 28 (9))
- Thomas Falconer, "Notes of a Journey through Texas and New Mexico, in the Years 1841 and 1842" (in the Journal of the Royal Geographical Society of London, 1844) (Box 28 (10))
- Pakenham correspondence, 1841-1842 (Box 28 (11))
- Miscellaneous Texas correspondence, 1832, 1836, etc. (Box 28 (12))
- Personal material, photographs, material relating to miscel laneous projects and interests, etc., material relating to publications (Box 28-29)
- Biographical and personal material, miscellaneous: resumes, membership cards, records of travel and personal possessions, tributes, certificates, Dictionary of American Scholars entries, etc., etc. (Box 28 (13))
- Newspaper clippings (personal) (Box 29 (1))
- Photographs (Box 29 (2))
- Official Correspondence of the Texas Revolution - material relating to publication (Box 29 (3))
- The Texas Revolution - material relating to publication, royalties, etc. (Box 29 (4))
- The Texas Revolution - reviews (Box 29 (5))
- Fleming lectures, 1950-52 - program, clippings, sketch (Box 29 (6))
- Comments on theses, papers, etc. - miscellaneous and undated (Box 29 (7))
- Student records, recommendations, etc. - miscellaneous and undated (Box 29 (8))
- Preliminary Report on the Archives of Colorado, Colorado Social Science Association, May, 1929 (Box 29 (9))
- Dictionary of American Biography, Dictionary of American History, Atlas of American History material (Box 29 (10))
- Historical publications - University series sets (typed lists) (Box 29 (11))
- Historical Records Survey of Tennessee (WPA, 1936-1938) material (Box 29 (12-13))
- Territory Papers - bills, acts, resolutions, etc., 1936-1963 (Box 29 (14))
- Texas Correspondence Project: "Editing and Publishing the Domestic Correspondence of the Republic of Texas," submitted to The National Historical Publications Commission, 1965 (Box 29 (15))
- Historical associations, societies, etc. - papers (Box 30-32)
- American Association for State and Local History, minutes, reports, etc., 1960-1968 (Box 30 (1-3))
- American Historical Association, minutes, reports, etc., 1941-1963 (Box 30 (4-5))
- American History Research Center, minutes, reports, etc., 1951-1958 (Box 30 (6-7))
- Mississippi Valley Historical Association and Review, minutes, reports, etc., 1936-1962 (Box 30-32)
- MVHA minutes, reports, etc., 1936-1938 (Box 30 (8))
- MVHA Memphis meeting, 1939 (Box 30 (9))
- MVHA minutes, reports, etc., 1939-1940 (Box 30 (10))
- MVHA minutes, reports, etc., 1940-1942 (Box 30 (11))
- MVHA minutes, reports, etc., 1943-1945 (Box 30 (12))
- MVHA minutes, reports, etc., 1946-1947 (Box 30 (13))
- MVHA minutes, reports, etc., 1948-1950 (Box 31 (1))
- MVHA minutes, reports, etc., 1951-1952 (Box 31 (2))
- MVHA minutes, reports, etc., 1953-1954 (Box 31 (3))
- MVHA minutes, reports, etc., 1955-1956 (Box 31 (4))
- MVHA minutes, reports, etc., 1967-1959 (Box 31 (5))
- MVHA minutes, reports, etc., 1960-1961 (Box 31 (6))
- MVHA minutes, reports, etc., 1963 (Box 31 (7))
- MVHA officers, 1907-1965 (Box 31 (8-9))
- MVHA Policy Committee, 1944 (Box 31 (10))
- MVHA Publications Committee (Box 31 (11))
- MVHA Secretary-Treasurer's Report, 1953-1957 (Box 31 (12))
- MVHA Secretary-Treasurer's Report, 1957-1959 (Box 32 (1))
- MVHA Secretary-Treasurer's Report, 1959-1962 (Box 32 (2))
- MVHA - miscellaneous (Box 32 (3))
- MVHR budget (travel, etc.), 1953-1962 (Box 32 (4))
- MVHR - miscellaneous (Box 32 (5))
- Southern Historical Association and Journal of Southern History, 1930's through 1960's (Box 32 (6-9))
- Tennessee Historical Society, 1943-, and Tennessee history (Box 32 (10))
- Texas State Historical Association (Box 32 (11))
- Southern Humanities Conference, 1946-1952 (Box 32 (12-13))
- Southern University Conference (Box 32 (14))
- Teaching materials from California, Colorado, Vanderbilt, Tulane, etc., including lecture and research notes, reading lists, syllabi, examinations, regulations, and miscellaneous publications. (Box 33)
- University of California (including Bolton material for fest schrift) (Box 33 (1))
- Colorado College - lecture and research notes (Box 33 (2-16), 34 (1-4))
- Colorado College - miscellaneous (Box 34 (5))
- Vanderbilt University - syllabi, reading lists, examinations, lecture outlines, etc. (Box 34 (6-11))
- Vanderbilt University - Ph.D. program (Box 34 (12))
- Vanderbilt University - degrees granted in history, 1931-1952 (Box 35 (1))
- Vanderbilt University - statistical analysis of graduate students in history (Box 35 (2))
- Vanderbilt University - History Department faculty, 1923-1953 (Box 35 (3))
- Vanderbilt University - miscellaneous (Box 35 (4))
- Tulane University - syllabi, examinations, lecture notes, etc. (Box 35 (5-10))
- Tulane University - miscellaneous (Box 35 (11-15))
- University of Houston - Ph.D. program (Box 36 (1-2))
- University of Houston - miscellaneous (Box 36 (3-4))
- University of Texas - miscellaneous (Box 36 (5))
- Lecture and research notes (Box 36 (6-14))
- Lecture and research notes (Box 37 (1-13))
- Lecture and research notes (Box 38 (1-6))
- Miscellaneous notes, lists, bills, invoices, etc. (Box 38 (7))
- Maps (Box 38 (8))
- Manuscripts by other persons -- addresses by Clifford L. Lord, James W. Silver (2), and Walter Prescott Webb (Box 38 (9-12))
- Manuscripts by other persons -- articles by Rudolf Freund, Weymouth T. Jordan (2), Walter Prescott Webb, Joe Mathews, and Thomas B. Alexander (Box 38 (13-15, 39 (1))
- Manuscripts by other persons -- poems, proposals, outlines, abstracts, etc. (Box 39 (2))
- Published articles by other persons -- clippings, off prints, etc. (Box 39 (3-7))
- Miscellaneous printed material (Box 39 (8-10))
- Miscellaneous printed material (Box 40 (1-6))
- 1 roll of microfilm, unidentified (Box 40 (7))
Incoming correspondence is arranged alphabetically, by author. Other information given is as follows: in parentheses, letterhead(s) used; number of items; in parentheses, date, if one letter only, or year(s), if more than one letter.
ABBOTT, Lucille (Edgewater Beach Hotel) - 1 (April l4, 1950)
ABBOTT, W. Lewis (Colorado College) - 2 (1929, 1930)
ABEHNETHY, Thomas P. (University of Virginia) - 5 (1935, 1942, 1943, 1948)
ABRAHAM, Lucille - 3 (1932, 1933)
ACKERMAN, D. F. (Springfield Public Schools) - 1 (July 11, 1952)
ADAIR, E. R. (McGill University) - 4 (1929, 1932)
ADAMS, Evelyn C. - 1 (Dec. 12, 1945)
ADAMS, Hbrace (Arkansas State Teachers College) - 1 (May 1, 1946)
ADER, Emile B. (University of Tulsa) - 1 (Oct. 22, 1952)
ADLER, Walter P. (Coleman E. Adler & Sons) - 1 (June 4, 1965)
AESCHBACHER, William D. (Mississippi Valley Historical Association) - 197 (1956-61, 1963, 1965, 1966, 1968) (including several letters to W.D.A. from other persons)
AGNEW, Dwight L. (Mississippi Valley Historical Review) - 3 (1946)
AITON, Arthur S. (University of Michigan, Committee on Latin American Studies) - 12 (1921-23, 1925, 1932, 1938, 1939, n.d.)
ALAMEDA County Charities Commission - 1 (June 27, 1937)
ALBRIGHT, Preston B. (Stanford University, Kemper Military School) - 8 (1930-32, 1944)
ALDERSON, William T. (Tennessee State Library and Archives, Tennessee Historical Commission, Tennessee Historical quarterly) - 17 (1953, 1954, 1956, 1957, 1959-61, 1963-66)
ALEXANDER, Arthur J. - 1 (May 28, 1945)
ALEXANDER, Thomas B. (U.S. Navy, Clemson Agricultural College, Georgia Teachers College, University of Alabama) - 56 (1942-49, 1951, 1952, 1954-60)
ALLEN, Carolyn E. (Social Science Research Council) - 1 (July 1, 1933)
ALLEN, Charles (University of New Mexico Press) - 3 ( 1947, 1948)
ALLEN, Jack (Peabody College) - 1 (Aug. 8, 1960)
ALLEN, Winnie (University of Texas Library) - 16 (1937, 1939, 1940, 1943, 1950, 1951)
ALLRED, John C. (University of Houston) - 1 (Sept. 13, 1965)
ALMGREN, Mary Louise - 1 (Sept. 25, 1934)
AMBLER, C. H. (tiest Virginia University) - 2 (1947)
ANDER, O. Fritiof (Augustana College and Theological Seminary) - 5 (1943, 1948, n.d.)
ANDERSON, Douglas - 5(1942, 1943, n.d.)
ANDERSON, Frances F. (Western Kentucky State Teachers College) - 1 (May 13, 1948)
ANDERSON, George L. (Colorado College, University of Kansas, Mississippi Valley Historical Association) - 14 (1940, 1950, 1951, 1955, 1956)
ANDRADE, Alberto M. (Biblioteca) - 1 (Mar. 2, 1943)
ANDREWS, Matthew Page (Committee on Publication) - 2 (1944)
ANDREWS, Rena M. (Winthrop College, Meredith College) - 8 (1945-47)
ANGLE, Paul M. (Illinois State Historical Library) - 4 (1944, 1945) (including 1 from F.L. Paxson)
APPLEWHITE, Davis (University of Redlands) - 15 (1946-53, 1959, 1969)
ARMBRISTER, Victor S. - 1 (Jan. 30, 1937)
ARMSTRONG, Neva (Southern Historical Association) - 5 (1959, 1964, 1966, 1967)
ASBURY, Samuel E. - 14 (1941, 194-47)
ATHERTON, Lewis (University of Missouri) - 2 (1938, 1959)
ATKINSON, Richard M. (U.S. House of Representatives) - 1 (Apr. 28, 1947)
AULT, Q. Cfulane University) - 1 (June 10, 1964)
BACARISSE, Charles A. (University of Houston) - 2 (1957)
BAILEY, J.O. (Southern Humanities Commission) - 9 (1948-49)
BAILEY, Kenneth K. (Cumberland College, New Mexico Military Institute, Indiana University, Texas Western College, North Texas State College, Louisiana State University) - 27 (1950, 1952-61)
BAKER, C. W. (Williams Printing Company) - 1 (May 22, 1941)
BAKER, Frank J. (Attorney at Law) - 1 (Aug. 31, 1921)
BAKER, Robert A. (Round Table Club) - 1 (Mar. 1, 1954)
BALDWIN, Ben R. (Florence State Teachers College) - 3 (1939, 1940)
BALL, Clyde - 1 (Dec. 4, 1937)
BANKS, Sidney (The Chamberlain) - 1 (Dec. 9, 1936)
BARBEE, David Rankin (Committee on American History) - 2 (1945, 1948)
BARD, W. E. - 3 (1938, 1942, 1954)
BARKER, E. C. (University of Texas) - 31 (1920-24, 1928, 1932-34, 1938-40 1938-40, 1946, 1949)
BARNES, DEMAS (University of Pittsburgh) - 1 (May 18, 1954)
BARNES, J. WARD (Eldorado Township High School) - 9 (1941, 1942, 1944, 1945)
BARNES, James A. (Temple University) - 6 (1941, 1943, 1946, 1947, 1951)
BARNES, Walter C. (University of California, University of Oregon, Smith College, Black Mountain College, Wellesley College) - 24 (1920, 1921, 1923, 1925, 1926, 1929, 1930, 1938, 1940-42, 1953) (including 1 each from Lennose Mills and J. Fred Hippy)
BARNHART, John D. (Journal of Southern History, Indiana University) -20 (1937, 1938, 1943-48)
BARRETT, Laura (Social Science Research Council) - 1 (n.d.)
BARROW, Mrs. A.M. - 1 (n.d.)
BARROWS, Albert L. (National Research Council) - 3 (1921, 1922, 1925)
BARTH, Werner H. (Kansas State College) - 1 (Sept. 16, 1958)
BASLER, Roy P. (Peabody College) - 1 (Aug. 5, 1947)
BASS, W. A. (Tennessee State Department of Education) - 4 (1937, 1938)
BATTEN, J. M. (Scarritt College) - 5 (1936)
BAUGHMAN, Howard E. (Hotel Hermitage) - 3 (1936)
BAUGHMAN, James P. (University of Houston) - 3 (1960, 1962)
BAUGHN, Milton (Arkansas A. & M. College) - 3 (1952, 1958, 1959)
BAXTER, James P. III (Harbard University) - 7 (1922-25, 1930)
BEACH, Leonard (Vanderbilt University) - 3 (1951, 1953)
BEALE, Howard K. (University of Wisconsin) - 3 (1944, 1951, 1952)
BEAN, W. G. (Washington and Lee University) - 4 (1949, 1950)
BEARDEN, H. D. - 1 (Aug. 6, 1944)
BEARDSLEY, W. W. (P.F. Collier & Son Corp.) - 1 (Oct. 10, 1938)
BEATTY, Richmond C. - 1 (n.d.)
BECKER, Carl (Cornell University) - 1 (Jan. 16, 1945)
BEGGS, William N. (State Historical... Society of Colorado) - 3 (1923, 1924)
BELISSARY, Constantine - 4 (1948, 1949, 1954) (including 1 from Harvie Branscomb)
BELK, N. C. (Lamar College) - 2 (1944, 1948)
BELL, Helen L. - 2 (1948)
BELLOT, H. Hale (University of London) - 3 (1937, 1940
BELSER, Thomas A., Jr. - 3 (1950, 1954, 1957)
BEMIS, Samuel F. - 9 (1934)
BENEDICT, A. B. (Vanderbilt University) - 1 (Oct. 17, 1952)
BENEDICT, Anne S. - 1 (June 19, 1953)
BENEDICT, H. Y. (University of Texas) - 4 (1932, 1934, 1935, 1937)
BENSON, Jerome (Phi Delta Kappa) - 2 (1963, n.d.)
BERDAHL, Clarence A. (University of Illinois) - 2 (1946)
BERNARD, V. L. (Whitney National Bank) - 4 (1940-41)
BERRY, Marie F. (New York Genealogical and Biographical Society) - 1 (Nov. 24, 1943)
BETTERSWORTH, John K. (Mississippi State College) - 1 (Jan. 30, 1950)
BICKLEY, J. L. (Canadian National Railways) - 1 (Nov. 22, 1932)
BIEBER, Ralph P. (Washington University) - 50 (1931, 1932, 1934, 1947-51) (including several letters to R.P.B. from other persons)
BIESELE, Rudolph L. (University of Texas) - 8 (1939, 1943, 1946-48)
BILLINGTON, Ray A. (Northwestern University) - 4 (1946, 1960, 1963)
BILLMANN, Calvin J. (Florida State University) - 2 (1954, 1961)
BINGHAM, Elizabeth Claughton - 2 (1939, 1950)
BINGHAM, Harold J. (Teachers College of Connecticut, University of California) - 4 (1946-48, 1956)
BINKLEY, F. M. - 4 (1933)
BINKLEY, R. W. - 2 (1931, 1933)
BINKLEY, Vera - 1 (March 24, 1933)
BISHOP, Aileen (Vanderbilt University) - 3 (1930, 1941)
BLACKSHARE, A. L., Jr. (National Distributors Association) - 1 (July 2 1925)
BLAKE, Clagette (Gertrude Blake Rich) - 8 (1950-53)
BLAKELY, Hunter B. (Queens-Chicora College) - 1 (June 9, 1939)
BLEGEN, Theodore G. (University of Minnesota, Minnesota Historical Society) - 18 (1938, 1944-46, 1948)
BLISS, Leslie E. (Huntington Library) - 1 (Aug. 6, 1951)
BLISS, Willard F. - 1 (Apr. l8, 1943)
BLOOM, Lansing B. (Historical Society of New Mexico, University of New Mexico, New Mexico Historical Review) - 9 (1926-28, 1931, 1933, 1934)
BLUE, W. R. (M.D.) - 1 (Sept. 29, 1943)
BLUE, WILLIAM L. (Foreign Service) - 14 (1934-42, 1950, n.d.)
BOEHM, Eric H. (Historical Abstracts) - 3 (1963)
BOHANNAN, Luther B. (University of Maryland) - 1 (Nov. l8, 1947)
BOLIN, J. S. (University of California) - 1 (Mar. 3, 1924)
BOLLING, Dick - 1 (Sept. 22, 1940)
BOLTON, Herbert E. (University of California, American Historical Asso ciation) - 31 (1919-26, 1928, 1930, 1931, 1936, 1938, 1940, 1941)
BQNHAM, H.S. (Texas House of Representatives) - 1 (Sept. 30, 1921)
BONINO, Louise (Random House) - 3 (1957)
BONNER, James C. (Georgia State College for Women) - 5 (1944, 1950)
BORDEN, Morton - 2 (1949)
BOROUGH, B. L. - 1 (Aug. 9, 1948)
BOSS, Josephine (University of California) - 1 (Jan. 20, 1931)
BOSWELL, J. M. (Cumberland College) - 1 (May 29, 1964)
BOUCHER, C. S. (University of Texas) - 1 (Jan. 29, 1922)
BOURNE, Henry E. (American Historical Review) - 11 (1931, 1932, 1935, 1936)
BOWLES, Gordon T. (Committee on International Exchange of Persons) - 2 (1949)
BOYCE, Gray C. (Northwestern University) - 1 (July 20, 1949)
BOYD, George H. (University of Georgia) - 1 (Feb. 26, 1947)
BOYD, Count R. (Yellow Pine Lumber) - 1 (Jan. 6, 1931)
BOYNTON, Paul L. (Austin State College) - 1 (Apr. 3, 1952)
BRADEN, Arthur (Transylvania College) - 3 (1936)
BRADLEY, Harold W. (Stanford University, Claremont Graduate School, Temple University, Vanderbilt University) - 14 (1943-46, 1948, 1949, 1951-53, 1955, 1958)
BRAMHALL, F. D. (Colorado Social Science Association) - 1 (Apr. 19, 1928)
BRANSCOMB, Harvie (Vanderbilt University) - 10 (1948-53) (including 1 to H.B. from Miriam Wilson)
BRAYER, Herbert O. (Colorado State Archives, Northwestern University) -2 (1946, 1952)
BREAKER, E. P. - 1 (n.d.)
BREARLY, H. C. (Peabody College) - 2 (194, 1953)
BRIDENBAUGH, Carl (Institute of Karly American History and Culture) - 2 (1947, 1949)
BRILEY, Beverly (Davidson County) - 1 (Aug. 8, 1951)
BRISTER, J. W. (Memphis State Teachers College) - 1 (May 29, 1936)
BROCKHAGEN, Fred R. (California Monthly) - 2 (1935)
BRODINSKY, B. P. (Educator's Washington Dispatch) - 1 (Sept. 14, 1946)
BROOKER, Wilfred L. (Ashland Public Schools) - 1 (Feb. 15, 1938)
BROOKS, Addie Lou - 24 (1932-34, 1940, 1942, 194, 1945)
BROOKS, Philip C. (Society of American Archivists, University of California, National Archives) - 8 (1931, 1932, 1938, 1939, 1942)